[MUSIC]
[음악]
In this module we talked about building sentiment analysis tools
이 모듈에서 분류를 통해 감성분석 도구
using classification.
만드는 법을 알아봤습니다
And now in this notebook, we are actually gonna go ahead and
이 노트북에서 하나
build one of those things.
만들어 보죠
So we're gonna build a sentiment analyzer for products.
상품 감성분석기를 만들겠습니다
So let's go ahead and get started.
시작하죠
Okay, so here we are on an iPython notebook as usual.
평소와 같은 IPython 노트북입니다
And again, I'm gonna hide the header.
헤더를 다시 감추죠
Before I hide the header, I want to change it's name, so let's rename the notebook.
그전에 노트북 제목을 바꾸겠습니다
So we're gonna call this Analyzing product sentiment,
상품 감성분석하기라고 하죠
since this is the notebook we're building, and
우리가 쓸 노트북이니
I'm gonna hide the header and I'm going to hide
헤더와 툴바를 감춰서
the toolbar just to have a little bit more space.
공간을 확보합니다
And we're gonna be using GraphLab Create today so
오늘 쓸 GraphLab Create을
I'm going to import GraphLab to get ourselves started.
도입하고 시작합니다
Here we go.
한번 해봅시다.
So the first thing that we're gonna do is read some data.
먼저 데이터를 읽어들입니다
So let's read some product review data.
상품 리뷰 데이터를 읽어들이죠
Let me read some product review data.
상품 리뷰 데이터 읽기
And this is real data set that we're going to read.
실제 데이터 세트를 쓰게 됩니다
So I'm gonna create an SFrame called products which uses
상품이라는 SFrame을 만들어서
graphlab.SFrame from a local file I've downloaded the data.
다운 받은 데이터 파일을 읽어들입니다
You are going to download the data too.
데이터를 다운 받아야 합니다
And this is some Amazon baby product data set.
아마존 유아용품 데이터 세트입니다
Okay.
좋아요.
We've downloaded that data, and so
데이터를 다운 받았으니
the first thing that we're gonna do is do a little bit of data exploration.
먼저 데이터 탐색을 좀 해봅시다
So, let's explore
함께
this data together.
데이터를 탐색하기
And this is fun.
재밌네요
So we have some product data, so let's just look at the head of this table.
상품 데이터가 있으니 표의 헤드를 봅니다
So the head is just the first few lines of this table that I've loaded up.
헤드는 표의 처음 몇 줄입니다
And so as you can see, it's composed of three things, the name of the product.
세 열로 구성되어 있는데 상품명,
So Planetwise Flannel Wipes for your product.
Planetwise Flannel Wipes가 상품명이죠
The review is Planetwipes are just okay but in my opinion something, something.
리뷰는 Flannel Wipes은 그럭저럭 괜찮지만 내 생각에...
And the rating is three.
별점은 3개고요
And it's out of five stars so a three is kind of middle of the road rating.
5개가 만점이니 3개는 중간 정도의 평가군요
While the Planentwise Wipe Pouch, this reviewer really liked it,
the Planentwise Wipe Pouch는 이 리뷰어가 정말 좋아했는지
they gave it a rating of five.
별점 5점을 줬습니다
So this is the data set that we're working with.
이게 우리가 작업할 데이터 세트입니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]